Hope you've enjoyed what you've seen so far, the synchronized events and the three meters for men and for women.
We're going to the highboard now, 10 meter platform competition.
And we are at the preliminary stage.
Well, we will whittle down 26 to 18 for the semifinal and then on to 12 for the final.
So quite a quick turnaround for the competitors here.
They will compete tonight UK time in the prelims and then the semifinals take place early tomorrow morning.
And then they'll be back in the evening for the final.
not maybe quite as many competitors as we imagined there would be but still quite a few so we're gonna lose eight tonight and most of the main diving countries are represented and a few who don't have a great depth in diving as well as you can see a big crowd here
to welcome the ten-meter competitors.
The men's, by the way, in case you're wondering, is on Friday, UK, and on Saturday evening will be the final.
But this is the preliminary of the women's ten-meter platform.
A man knows all about ten-meter, having won the Synchro Silver Medal in 2004 with Pete Waterfield.
Here's Leon Taylor.
What a great shot of the the 10 meter board there as we were hovering above it and then we can see it now from the more of a deck level.
You can see the big drop down cam just to the right of the 10 meter.
We're going to be up close and personal with the divers following them all the way down and into the into the water.
And there is the list of the divers and we'll see the list of the dives that they're going to do a little later on.
We will have a couple of 16 year olds in here and a 15 year old as well.
So it is sometimes considered a young person sport.
And also a fourteen year old.
Yeah, fourteen, fifteen and two sixteen year olds.
So barely out of nappies and they'll be competing on the women's ten meter platform here.
And I was looking at the stats on a couple of the divers.
about six or seven stone went through and they're quite small but I thought I can't even remember when I was six stone doing quite nice and for those of you watching around the world we'll convert that into pounds and kilograms for you later on.
We do the whole service here and if you want a valet afterwards we'll sort that out for you.
Okay, so what are we expecting?
Well, it's a bit of a marathon actually because the preliminary scores do not carry through to the semi-finals and of course the semi-finals scores do not carry through to the finals.
So, you know, you could win the prelim and then it actually makes no difference.
Diving steady, getting through and shuffling of the pack, so to speak.
So 18 divers going through.
So we're only going to lose eight, which isn't that many, but it'll be highly contested.
And the girls have to get up early tomorrow morning, so they won't be to bed until late tonight.
Finishing here in several hours' time, up to three hours, this competition is scheduled to run for.
Late finish back to the Olympic Village, some food, try and sleep full of adrenaline is never easy and then up early in the morning to come in and practice those dives once again.
They're the all-important judges, seven judges in the individual competitions.
I'll just run through how the judging works.
The judges mark the dive on execution out of a maximum of 10.
So if they think it's okay they'll maybe give it a five, five and a half if they think it's good.
maybe a 7 or a 7.5.
If they think it's really, really good they might even go 8.5 and 9.
Those scores are then collated.
The two highest and two lowest judges' scores are discounted.
They will be shown on the screen with lines through them to leave three scores that count.
These three raw scores are totaled together and then multiplied by the degree of difficulty for that particular dive.
The degree of difficulty per dive is calculated on how complex the dive is.
That gives a total score for that dive.
Each of the five dives count.
It's the cumulative score that counts towards the placings at the end of round five.
I hope that makes sense, which we'll revisit during this long competition.
we shall indeed and we still get asked about those marks who lines through hopefully now we've nailed that so to speak in terms of what you need to know about the scoring if it's got a line through it it doesn't count if it hasn't it does that's what it comes down to basically and then you multiply that by the degree of difficulty we're not going to be up in the three point eight stakes here like we will be in the men's three point three i think is probably the uh the top isn't it
The divers of course submit all their dives before and they have to go in different directions.
We can talk you through as the competition unfolds.
There's actually six groups of dives and the girls have to do five dives each from a different group.
See Brittany Viola there, just going through her visualization.
She's visualizing the dive.
You can see her eyelids fluttering there.
Don't worry, she hasn't fallen asleep.
She's just preparing herself mentally to go with her physical preparation because this needs to be right, needs to count.
If she wants to make it through, she knows she needs five solid dives.
25-year-old from America, plenty of experience behind her.
always tough to go first.
She is just enacting the dive on the top of the board before she gets involved and getting some water out of her ears there.
Hence the head banging or head shaking and the towel being thrown down the shammy just to keep the drivers dry so they can hold on to the shape.
First dive then for the USA, two American competitors in this competition.
Brittany Viola is first and it's a forward three and a half somersaults with pike 3.0, the degree of difficulty.
Remember the three marks multiplied by the degree of difficulty for the total score.
Wow, to ooze and ours from the spectators.
It's very impressive, this sport.
Plenty of support here for the US diving team.
They've already got a bag full of medals from Brittany Viola.
We'll be looking to for safe passage through these preliminaries.
The pike shape folding at the hips, beautiful shape, great aerial work.
That's a good dive for the American to open up with.
She sets her marker down.
and a pretty good market it is to seventy point five zero the mark on the right hand side of your screen and the one on the left hand side means that she is number one in the rankings obviously she would be because she is the first competitor now from france audrey laboe going for a slightly less tariff dive two point eight to open up with inwards two and a half somersaults in the pike position
Or over rotating, the dive tips over.
The girls haven't got a lot of time to squeeze all these rotations in.
It's sometimes very easy to misjudge the entry into the water.
And that's what we're seeing there from Audrey, 27 years old now.
So she's one of the more experienced athletes in the field.
They see over rotating, throwing up too much splash, still landing as I was talking, which means the judges will penalise that.
And of course we will be down to 18 at the end of this competition for the original 26, so she has to make sure she's in that field.
And it's not the most auspicious of starts for Audrey.
6.5s across the main part of her scoring.
53.20 total mark now.
Megan Benfito, fourth in Shanghai at the World Championships, fourth in Rome at the World Championships.
What an incentive to go one better here in London at the Olympics.
Oh, very steady.
Very precise.
Great entry into the water.
Rip entry.
Canadians having some good results here.
Of course, this young lady, along with her partner, got a bronze medal in a very exciting 10-meter platform synchro.
Here she is individually today.
And that's a steady start.
Eights incoming.
And top of the leaderboard at this early stage.
Only three divers in, of course.
Yeah, it was three point zero degree of difficulty.
So we can make a direct comparison with Viola and she goes further, goes higher and goes better.
Seventy three point five zero for the Canadian.
The first of two Canadians we will see.
Now, here comes the Olympic champion, world champion, Chen Ruolin.
Three point zero four, three and a half again like the opening dive.
Well, as you'd expect,
on the money from this last I can't believe that she's only 19 years old and she's already Olympic champion at the age of 15 truly extraordinary that's what we come to expect from the Chinese of course not having their own way in the pool last night I'm sure the rest of the world is
a little bit more enthused and you know, upbeat about taking on these two girls today but will certainly take some beating and forward three and a half.
Lots of tape holding it together.
Training so hard but eight point fives to count into the lead.
Well, of course, they do hit the water at thirty-four,
and some go a bit quicker.
Yuriy Prokopchuk of Ukraine.
Four and three and a half again.
This is a very popular opening dive for the competitors with Pike.
or she does okay maybe just turning as she went into the water so i could see both ankles as she went in let's have a look at the replay to see if what i was seeing actually happened or whether i'm making it up let's have a look so she's squeezing into a pike shape needs to be a little bit tighter there as she goes in yeah didn't look quite where it needed to be on the finish it'll probably get sevens
It keeps her with an okay start.
66.
Clickety-click for Iulia Prokopchuk.
Now the big raw greets the arrival of Stacey Powell, the first of two Britons involved in this competition.
She's going for a high tariff dive, one of the higher tariff dives to start off with.
And as anybody who's watched our coverage over the years will know, I get the jitters with the arm stands.
And I still believe outdoors, it should be worth more than 3.2, but it is worth 3.2 indoors.
I keep banging that drum.
I shake my head every time you say it.
I'll stand.
I'll stand back at double somersault one and a half twist.
There's no wind blowing through here.
Fortunately, so no outside elements to affect Stacey Powell's opening dive.
Oh what a confident start coming in her opening dive in the Olympic Games as if she wouldn't be nervous enough already decides to show how confident she is by starting with this arm stand steady balance bends the knees flicks off one and a half twist double somersault of course hands to hands it's a very neat and tidy dive just you know leaving a little bit of a dish as she went into the water which means she'll probably only get sevens from the judges but just showing her confidence
Yeah, she was here and there a little bit in the shape.
Maybe going into the twist a little bit early showing on the replay there.
Well done, Stace.
Good start.
Sixty-seven point two zero and we can definitely promise you loads of chick flicks tonight.
On to Naomi Baki of Italy.
Born in Hungary, representing Italy.
Yeah, you can see lots of the girls opening up with this, the forward three and a half.
As I mentioned at the beginning of the competition, each dive has to be in a different group.
This is the forward group.
This is the most popular.
No girls here will do the forward four and a half that we see from the men.
The forward three and a half pikes and that's a very, very tidy dive from the Italian.
No one's giving it away anything yet.
All dive is landing pretty consistently.
Let's see what the judges think of that dive.
3.0 degree of difficulty.
72 puts her in third place.
Now just on the lower end of the tariff.
To start off with, not going for broke straight off, is Kristen Stur of Germany.
Inward two and a half somersaults with Pike.
2.8 as you'll see.
So she has a bit of ground to make up on the slightly higher tariff dives in round one.
Oh she's going for a little bit of an easier degree of difficulty lots of girls going for the inward three and a half in the tuck position which carries a higher degree of difficulty this the two and a half in the pike position spinning forwards it's important you miss your toes on the diving board which she does but she moves her hips back a little bit too much on the start and spins too slowly finishing very low that's a very poor dive to start with from this experienced German diver 29 years old she's been there and done it several times before but today
leaves herself on the back foot after dive number one and leaves herself at the bottom of the rung in terms of the pecking order now eighth place for the German after her opening dive now Monique Gladding 3.2 again like her British teammate Stacey Powell going for
High tariff or relatively high tariff dive.
So if the women it is 3.2.
Back two and a half somersaults, one and a half twists, pike.
Is Monique glad to be here at all.
We'll no doubt relate the story about why she's very glad to be competing at this Olympics.
After we've seen her opening dive.
Oh, it's a steady start from both of the British girls.
Monique, 31 years old, bumped into her family on my way in here to commentate today and they're so excited to see her.
Missed out eight years ago before Athens, missed out in Beijing.
Here she is competing in her first Olympic Games, starting with one of more difficult dives, 3.2, one and a half twist into the two and a half somersaults.
She's had some tough challenges coming into this with injuries recently, neck and some various other things but she's here and she'll be fighting for a place in the semifinal.
And she matches her British teammate Stacey Powell.
They open up with sixty-seven point two zero both.
Sixteen years of age.
Oh, well, there you go.
She wasn't wanting to hang around, wanted to get the dive done straight away.
She's only tiny, isn't she?
Ended up short as she went in the water there, which will cost her.
She'll only get sevens at best on this.
All looks good so far.
Just let's go a little bit too early under the water, hitting her on the front of her body there.
Splash being thrown up, not too much because there isn't very much of her to make any splash.
But this young lady, well I've been watching her in training, she's formidable.
She'll be challenging her teammate Chen Ru Lin, but not with a dive like that.
I wonder if she has got a Chinese upgrade on these scores.
Here they come.
7.5s for Hu Yudan.
And 67.50 is her opening mark now from People's Republic of Korea.
It's Kim Woo Hyang.
And this is a dive we've seen already quite a few times.
Four and three and a half somersaults with Pike.
Very popular dive first round.
This one with Pike.
Oh, wow.
She really attacked that, didn't she?
Probably gave it a little bit too much.
And you can quite clearly say the over rotation into the into the water.
She absolutely motors this.
Landing on the end.
Divers choosing to use the towel.
Maybe it gives a bit more grip, but it's certainly diver preference.
But look at that.
Over she goes.
Four fours, four point fives.
Probably that is quite far over a vertical.
And she'll have some work to do.
On the golf course for a minute there, shouting four.
Five, four and a half, and a five for Kim Nguyen.
And that's not going to do her chance at progression much good at all.
Here's Brittany Brobin, 16 years of age from Australia.
The lowest tariff we've seen so far, 2.7 on this reverse, two and a half semisaults with Tuck.
Oh, it's a beautiful dive to open up with.
You're only 16 years old.
I haven't seen much of this girl at all.
A new girl on the block.
There's her coach.
He likes to start to reverse.
So you're standing forwards, jumping away from the diving board, spinning backwards.
Beautiful technique.
Just tipping over a vertical slightly.
That's going to get eights and 8.5s.
It's a beautiful start.
Very confident for a young 16 year old.
So, the Aussies on the board, whether it be three meter or ten meter, have been quite confident so far.
Eight point fives across the board for her.
Gives her sixty-eight point eight five with that opening round dive.
Second of the Italians now, Brenda Spaziani.
And again, and two point eight, Sayoni.
So, it would be well beyond my compass and probably yours at home as well.
Inward two and a half
Well, I think you could see the nerves there at home, couldn't you?
So she was twitching.
The cameraman zoomed right in on the thumbs and fingers.
She's a little bit close to the diving board.
You can see her flattening her feet there.
This is the danger on this dive.
It's very easy to tip your toes on it.
It doesn't hurt, but it does throw you off.
Look at this tip.
Oh, no, she just misses the diving board.
It does put her boots on as she goes by in order to miss it.
It's a technical diving term, putting your boots on.
I'm sure you're getting into it now.
Look at that beautiful super slow motion into the entry there from the fixed cameras.
A little bit off the mark for Brenda.
54.60 and those indulging in the Leon Taylor drinking game.
That's probably your first one of the evening.
Now, Carolina Mendoza Hernandez of Mexico.
Again, it's a forward three and a half somersaults with Pike.
And again, you can compare and contrast this dive with plenty of the others in the first round.
Well, this is an exciting diver.
She's only 15 years old and I'm just looking down to her list of dives and she is bringing out the big guns for her competition here.
This is her easiest dive at three point zero.
Everything else is really, really tricky and she's got a lot of tape on there on her back.
Again, we discuss this every time.
Lots of the divers held together by sticky tape.
This young Mexican just on the well, down the right hand side of her back there.
Obviously suffering as many of these divers too do because of the strains of the sport.
Seven point fives and sevens will count towards the total.
And she gets sixty four point five zero.
Second of the Canadians, Rosaline Fillon.
It's going to be that, yeah, you've seen it before and you'll see it many more times.
Every diver will do this pretty much.
It's a four, three and a half, seven sorts with Pike.
With three point zero degree of difficulty.
Very steady just like her teammate.
Of course, they were bronze medalists only last week and that's going to make you feel good coming into your individual event.
Riding on a high although they've had a bit of a wait but no more waiting around now.
This is it.
You're in prelims.
Just a little over vertical.
Strong, powerful takeoff.
Squeezing into the pike.
There we go.
So, what'd you get for that?
Sevens multiplied by three.
Degree of difficulty gives you 63.
Now, I was expecting Melissa Wu in the synchro the other day, but she wasn't there because her partner and she didn't make it through, so here she is in the individual.
Yep, she'll have a point to prove here.
Had to wait patiently all week watching her teammates.
Diving, being on right from the start, lands perfectly on the end.
Long legs.
Looks good when she's spinning around.
Just a little bit of splash as she goes in, but that's a really solid start.
Here come eights, maybe even eight point fives.
It's a good dive.
Yeah, nice solid start for Melissa Wu.
Had to wait a long time, not having been involved in the 10 meter synchro the other day.
Back in with three eights, 72.
Smile from the coach, kiss from the coach.
Happy.
Now, Maria Coyo of Germany.
Yeah, you're getting used to seeing this dive now.
Just probably a little bit too much splash being thrown up there.
I didn't know so much about this German.
He's done very well to make the team highly contested on the platform.
Watched her teammate Falter earlier looking to pick up from that.
He's done a reasonable job.
Just a little low on the water throwing up the
There we go.
Look at the view of the Aquatic Center.
That front-on shot there with the Oz iconic diving boards.
Certainly are.
Many, many tons of concrete's gone into that.
How many hours of preparation for Maria Curio brings her 6.5s in the opening round dive.
Here's another person who was involved in the synchro the other day, Amdana Pang of Malaysia.
Oh, well done, Panda Leather.
That's a beautiful dive.
Yeah, it works very hard again.
Often has injury troubles.
Let's see how much tape she's sporting.
Yeah, both ankles, both wrists.
But she certainly gets going there.
Look at that pike shape.
She almost has a chin on her ankles.
That's incredible flexibility and there's a beautiful dive as well.
Should put her top of the pile or thereabouts after the first round or so far.
Yeah, I just didn't try that at home.
Putting your chin on your ankles.
You might do yourself a mischief.
Leave it for the divers.
And her opening score is seventy-two.
Quite a popular one.
Three three divers on that mark.
Seventy-two.
Chen leading the way.
Ben Fito in second.
Kim Jin Ok from People's
Four, three and a half.
You get to know this very well by now.
Oh, it's a very tidy dive.
Good entry into the water.
Just a little over a vertical as she goes in.
Otherwise a very good effort.
Strong, powerful takeoff.
Look at these divers.
All plenty of tape everywhere.
Ankles, calves, trying to hold themselves together.
It's a very solid start.
Kim will be very pleased with that.
I wonder if the coaches will.
You never really know who the coach is.
Another seventy-two.
That seems to be the popular score tonight.
Four girls on that.
In equal third place.
Annie Rivera of Cuba.
Slight difference for you this time.
Lower degree of difficulty.
Two point eight for the
Very very safe distance from the diving board.
I mentioned last time we watched this dive.
It is only 2.8 degree of difficulty Moves it away a safe distance so she didn't have to flatten her feet as she goes by There you go, and then just hangs on a little bit too long in the pike shape It just tips over a vertical look at the splash going back towards the diving board fives probably for that effort and some work to do and
How generous the judge is feeling.
Five point fives willing to account.
So three scores discounted, four scores discounted, and three will remain in place.
Tracy Turkiet of Malaysia has opted for the dive that pretty much everybody else in the first round has the four with three and a half.
yeah just rolling into the water not quite straightening out as she went in so the judges will take some marks off for that even though the entry was clean minimal splash she didn't quite complete the dive in time so yeah lots of divers opting for the forward three and a half in the pike position it is 3.0
Some of the girls might do it in the tuck position, but all girls choosing to do the forward group.
Of course they've got six groups to choose from.
The forward is only one of six.
So we will see some variance, but it seems to be a popular opener in the women's competition.
Yeah, 66 this time, 7.5 times two, and seven up to a total.
I was mentioning about weights and heights earlier on.
Here is Katie Bell, 6'11", or if you prefer, 48 kilograms.
or around about 86 pounds.
Just get yourself composed.
Smile, take a little bit of perspiration off the fingers.
Just count yourself in, I think.
Well, she was having a chat with herself before she ran off the end of the 10-metre board there.
I wonder what she was saying.
I was curious.
We weren't quite close enough to the speakers to hear.
I think Bob's guess may be accurate of counting herself in.
you know sometimes divers do a little I used to talk to myself only in my head I used to say some you know positive things yeah but I'm speaking into the microphone now so you can all hear my thoughts lucky you all at home anyway not so lucky for young miss Bell just over a vertical as she went in you can see how small she's there next to her a very tall coach it's quite a contrast isn't it yeah Casey Bell dropping a clanger on her opening round
Now, Paola Espinosa Sanchez.
Oh, Mexico, watch this girl.
She's pretty decent.
Bronze medalist in the world's last year.
Oh, there's the commentator.
Yeah, right.
Right for her now.
Already silver medalist in the 10 meter synchro.
And as Bob has mentioned, a phenomenal athlete known for her spring and power and dynamic diving and not so well known for landing over a vertical on an opening dive.
However,
It was a good dive apart from the fault on the entry.
So she's very high and it was a good shape in the air.
So they're not going to go to town on her so much.
Just making her way back there.
So on the marks, yes, seven.
She gets away with it there.
Maybe a reputation saving her.
Yeah, she will improve.
I'm sure she'll be back.
Well, I hope she'll be back for the semi-final because she's a very entertaining and very classy individual when it comes to this competition.
Now, the second of the arm stands.
I'm not looking.
Yulia Coltanova.
Not quite as complicated as Stacey Powers.
The arm stand forward double somersault, one twist with three.
Still difficult enough.
Oh, what an entry.
What an absolute beauty of an entry.
Just disappeared into the water.
Hardly a ripple of splash.
Wow.
That really is quite something.
Armstand balance flicking off.
Here we go.
There's the one twist.
It's the double somersault.
It's tricky.
There's a lot going on.
I think it's more complicated than the three point one.
But there we go.
What an entry.
Maybe squeeze some nines from the judges.
Hardly a droplet of splash as she goes in, even on the slow motion.
And that dive takes her into the lead.
79.05 ahead of Chen and Benfito who are four, one and two.
They're now two and three and the Russian.
24th diver in the competition goes into the lead.
Now Mai Nakagawa on Japan.
Inward two and a half with Mike.
Oh, beautiful dive from Nakagawa.
Yep, there we are, the friends and family here from all over the world to support these athletes just touching their toes on the diving board there.
I didn't see that in real speed.
I don't think the judges will see it either because she didn't falter, but she did dunk her toes on the diving board.
Now, because it didn't affect the dive and the judges don't get the replays, I think she got away with it.
Well done.
That's a poker face as well, isn't it?
She wasn't going to give anything away there.
71.40 for Nakagawa.
Now the last diver, the youngest diver in the competition.
Wanted to get along with it too.
Cool.
Well, no guesses there what happened.
Here's Splash giving it away.
leg it into the end of the diving board.
All looks okay so far and that's now is when you want to come out.
Oh, just over she goes.
Lowest scoring diver of the competition from the youngest diver in the competition.
Kim from Korea.
Fourteen years of age she is and that will have hurt.
Give me a total of thirty-six and the coach is not going to be relenting in terms of
And the end of the first round of the Women's 10m platform.
And the preliminary standings after round one.
Potanova, Chen and Benfito, one, two, three, plenty in fourth place.
Top eighteen, remember, going through and at the moment both of the British divers are going through.
just uh well I hope they don't have a dive off I'm sure they won't happen but the bottom joint 17th and these are the ones who have a little bit of work to do even at this early stage and I think the two Kims are probably not going to be involved in the shake-up at the end even at this stage
Very impressive arena this in the Aquatic Center in Olympic Park and a beautifully shaped 10 meter board really artistically.
Everything about this venue has been artistic.
Let's see whether
Brittany Viola can be artistic on her arm stand back at double somersault one and a half twist three point two the degree of difficulty and about thirty feet up and no margin forever.
Those feet right over the edge.
Hands taking all the weight.
All right, it's dramatic, isn't it?
Balancing on the end, you can see, put these mum there, holding her breath as her daughter lifted herself up with perfect control into that arm stand, bending the knees, it's called the flick, one and a half twist, squares it up nicely on the end, finishes accurately on the water.
Nice second round dive for Viola, looks very, very focused.
I've not seen her look so focused, working for her so far.
Yeah, good mark for her.
Coach will never be happy, of course, and there's things she can improve on it for the next time around.
Brian, she's there.
73.60 for Viola of the USA.
And now Audrey LeBeau.
And a 53.2 to start with.
So she's got a bit of ground to make up already.
She's not into the threes yet.
2.9 degree of difficulty on this back.
Two and a half somersaults with Pike for the French woman.
Oh, it's a very good entry, just short of vertical, but she manages to hold the tension, hold her body tension, and get a very, very good rip entry into the water.
It's a relatively easy dive in comparison to some of the others.
2.8 degree, 2.9 degree of difficulty, I beg your pardon.
But when it's done like that, that'll get a reasonable score and keep her, well, upping her game actually from the first round dive.
Yeah, certainly a big improvement from the first round.
53 up to 68 now.
The degree of difficulty was slightly improved and the dive itself was very much improved.
Third round after the first round.
Let's rearrange these words to make a sentence.
Megan Benfito of Canada going with a back three and a half somersaults.
Look at the difficulty.
Right at the top of the shop here.
3.3 on this one.
oh she's landed it very well indeed it's yeah high risk so audrey before her opting for the backward two and a half in the pike position 2.9 degree of difficulty this the backward three and a half 3.3 degree of difficulty so if you get it right it can work for you and megan has done just that once you get on this seven halves and eights i think and that'll leave her smiling after a second round dive i'm sure
The marks without the lines through them, the ones that count, eight, eight, and seven point five multiplied by the degree of difficulty.
That's how we arrive at seventy-seven point five five.
Now, the Olympic and world champion, Chen Ruolin, second after round one, in with three and a half, Wittak, with three point two in terms of degree of difficulty.
Oh, throwing up more splash than I was expecting.
The entry seemed to be, well, all in order, if you like, so she disappeared, but then this big volcano of splash came up afterwards.
Takeoff is very good.
Seems to be all good from here, up right into the water, so vertical entry, but look at that, bubbles up.
It's like a geyser.
I don't know what they're called.
Those things that bubble up water.
What are they called, Bob?
If you say geyser around here, you get a completely different response.
I mean, the East End, remember?
Yep.
That's Chenrulian.
Yeah, geyser will be fine.
Yeah, I think it works.
Now on to Iulia Prokopchuk of Ukraine.
And we're upping the stakes for most of them now.
In with three and a half somersaults.
Three point two with Tuck.
Fourteenth after round one.
If she stays there, she will be fine for the semi.
Oh, very good indeed.
Finishing a little bit low on the water.
Teammates like it.
Gavasha, who featured yesterday's final, cheering on his teammate here.
There we go.
Safe distance from the diving board, yes.
I know it's not far away, but it's safe.
A little bit low on the water, but she's very sneaky on that finish.
That could get 80 points.
And if it does, then she'll be way up there after the second round.
Anything in the 70s is good.
Oh, that's a bit of a lap.
80.
The nine won't count.
High mark.
But 80 is a high mark, and that will move her up the standings quite some way.
Decent opening for Stacey Powell with the arm stand.
She's got that one out of the way, and now she can concentrate on another high tariff dive.
3.3 is a high tariff program.
There's a lot of risk attached to it, but if it works out, then you go shooting into the semifinal.
That's obviously the plan for Stacey Powell.
Back three and a half somersaults with Tuck.
3.3 for the first of the Britons diving in round two.
Oh that could prove to be critical.
Stacey with some work to do.
This is the only dive in a program that could potentially have led her down.
It's her highest degree of difficulty
It's the one that could have gone wrong.
And unfortunately for Stacey, it is the one that does go wrong.
She lets go of her shape way too early there.
Loose in the lower back, bending the knees.
She's going to get thumped by the judges on that.
The marks will be very low.
Here's the drop down cam.
Just showing where it all goes wrong.
There we are.
That isn't going to be very nice either.
Don't want to see the scoreboard.
Stacey had a walk away by a year.
29.70.
Only those threes count.
Agony for her.
The only good thing is it's not a big field, so there is time to repair the damage.
Other people, of course, could fault her on their dives.
Here comes back key of Italy.
Back two and a half somersaults with Pike.
Again, only two point nine.
Not into the threes yet.
Yeah, playing it safe.
We saw Stacey Powell from Team GP there, ending her back three and a half, which is an option in this backward movement group.
Very, very short back to here playing safe, and it proves a better gamble.
That'll get mid-60s.
Very tidy.
Only 2.9 degree of difficulty, but it's performed very well indeed.
Look at that, super slow motion.
Difficult to be zoomed in that far on the dive up.
We get an idea of what's going on.
Solid from Bakke.
65.25 will do her a power of good in terms of getting that top 18 place.
Now to Christian Stirr of Germany.
who is in the threes.
Three point two on his back.
Two and a half somersaults.
One and a half twists performed in the pike position.
She needs a few points.
She's back in twenty second after a fairly poor first round dive.
Right on cue she required some more points and this is the dive to do it on her most difficult in the program 3.2 degree of difficulty Yeah, poor opening inwards actually She's got her wrist heavily strapped up there, but didn't seem to affect her entry into the water One and a half twist two and a half somersaults and then yeah sneaks it in there with a rip entry that will help her out
Seven point fives, a smile, a little nod at the coach and seventy-two for Stewart.
Monique Lanning.
Twelve equal after round one.
Now she has gone from a high tariff dive to start off with to a much more low tariff dive for round two and taking all the time that she can for preparation.
Is there a time limit, Neil?
Under the referee's discretion, that's right, but the referee has only just blown the whistle now, so Monique will have as much time as she needs within reason.
If the referee thinks she's taking too long, they can restart, but no worries.
Inwards, two and a half somersaults with Pike, 2.8 from Monique.
Oh, it's very good.
I was holding my breath then.
The reason being is that this particular move of dive is the dive that Monique dramatically last year hit her head on the diving board.
It was a different dive to this one.
It was the inward three and a half.
She hit her head on the diving board and needed to be rescued from the bottom of the pool unconscious in Russia by her teammate Nicholas and Robinson Baker.
Fortunately, she's made this amazing comeback.
Now this dive that she's been performing instead, in with two and a half in the pike position, your feet can come a little bit close and she has been hitting her feet in training, so it's been a really tough time.
You can see the relief on her face there.
Sevens across the board.
Almost, look, I've got away with that one.
Sevens and 58 because the low degree of difficulty, but puts her up into the top six for now.
Who you Dan?
The sixteen-year-old from China in with three and a half with Tuck.
Three point two for her second dive.
Oh, it's a good entry but it is over.
So, I say good entry as in clean with not very much splash.
Look at Rue Michelle there saying, look, she went flying over and yes, she did.
Rue should come up here and provide the commentary.
Here we are.
In with three and a half in the tuck position.
Nothing wrong with that tuck position.
There she goes.
Whoa, arching in the lower back.
Over she goes.
That'll get sevens, I think.
Well, they should get sevens.
Because, well, yeah, it's a shame really.
She did all the hard work.
A bit better than sevens.
Eight and seven point five and it's been great pleasure working with you.
Now, on to Kim Un Hyang of the People's Republic of Korea.
And again, the aid of a towel.
In with three and a half, with tuck, three point two.
Again, a little bit of ground to make up after that.
That's an auspicious start, shall we say.
Oh, that's a better second round dive.
She's having a good think about it.
Divers balancing on their tiptoes.
Intends not to be so sensible to hang around for too long.
Your legs can get tired just on your tiptoes, does it work?
Anyway, Kim making a better effort on their second round dive there.
In with three and a half.
Your hair comes pretty close, doesn't it?
Never very far away.
That's a little bit too close.
We're just talking about Monique Gladdy hitting her head.
You can see how it happens.
There we go.
Hands up.
How many of you at home have recoiled on a couple of those dives tonight because that is immensely close and that concrete is unforgiving as Mike Gladding found out in Russia.
Now, on to Brittany Robin of Australia in with three and a half for her as well.
Tuck position three point two.
Oh, that's such a shame.
She was completing the dive with ease, in fact, and then she just maybe panicked a little bit and comes out of the dive a little bit early.
That's a safe distance from the diving board.
And then just stretches forward a little bit too much, ending short of vertical there.
So six and a halfs probably, which is a shame because if she waited in a touch shape a little bit longer, she'd have been on for eight maybe.
Waiting for the marks to be calibrated, calculated and put on the scoreboard.
6.5 is for Brittany Broben and 62.40 the total mark.
She is probably not going to be moving up from her position of 10th after round one.
Brenda Spaziani of Italy.
For three and a half somersaults with Pike.
3.0
Just finishing short as she goes in there.
It's a difficult dive, 3.0.
You need to really attack the takeoff.
Brenda does attack it but she doesn't quite get in a pike shape.
You can see there's some daylight in between her thighs and chest there.
Needs to squeeze in a little bit tighter in order to make the dive with ease and give her a chance to get that entry right.
and the marks please judges coming up now 6.0 right across the board times three working out basic maths for you this time 54 is her total mark right arm stand time oh goody
A back triple somersault with tuck.
3.3, the degree of difficulty.
And again, I think we might find that Endoza Fernandez might just take a little while over this.
Split step right.
Hands positioned right.
Wait until she's in a solid position.
Wavering a bit.
Ready to go.
She does a good job.
Of course, the she's under the judges.
Well, the the judges are actually judging her right from the, you know, as soon as the referee's whistle goes.
So, as soon as she starts to lift up, you know, she's wobbling around.
The judges will see that and they could take off some some marks for not showing control but she seemed pretty controlled to me.
Ending the dive a little bit short but it's a
holding on to the top of her kneecaps there.
She does very well to stay in a tuck shape.
Throwing up too much splash for eights, but sevens maybe.
It is sevens and a six point five.
Joseph being quite tight on their scoring tonight for the most part.
Sixty seven point six five for Mendoza Hernandez.
He's not going to hide away now.
Roslyn Filion back three and a half somersaults with Tuck.
3.3 saving her armstand a little bit later just inside that cut off of the top 18 in 17th.
Oh yeah indeed it was a big dive and we've seen a couple of the girls faltering on this one Stacey Powell is an example this time Rosaline actually hanging on to a tuck shape long enough she's running out of room holding on to the tops of her knees there she pops her feet right up and just tips over tries to save it by bending her knees and then causes a bit of a boom water-wise as she goes in that's not going to get too much over 50 points at that level oh interesting
Rosley and Filion shaking the room with that boom 5.5 and a 4.5 for the Canadian not quite what she wanted at this stage
On to Melissa Wu of Australia.
It's arm stand time, everybody.
Back double somersault, one and a half twists, free position.
Explain that very quickly, Leon, free position.
Yeah, when the diver isn't rotating for more than one somersault out of a twist, it means a free position.
So you don't actually hold a position for more than half a somersault.
So you see Melissa stay relatively straight throughout this and then just re-pike on the finish to enter the water.
3.2 degree of difficulty.
No, she does a really superb job on that finish.
Yep, there's a lot going on.
You're flicking off your hands.
One and a half twist, double somersault.
There's a lot to get in in such a short amount of time.
There's a one and a half twist.
Re-pikes, there we are, the free position and very tidy in.
That's going to get eights and that's going to move her up the field.
Let's see what the total mark is.
After a 72 to start, she follows up with a 76.80, quite solid from Wu, and she is up to third place right now.
On to Maria of Germany.
Three point two arm stand.
Back double somersault one and a half twist again in the free position.
I haven't seen that an awful lot in other dive competitions.
So I thought we'd just underline it's not tuck or pike.
Let's just say it slowly because I normally say puck and tyke.
It's a good dive.
Running out of room a little bit.
She goes into there a little bit scrappy Here we are bending the arms trying to flick up generate height from the arms as you can see here It's good.
No, I'm probably being a little unfair.
She did have time to finish it off properly
It'll get sevens and that's better than her first round effort, which she'll be pleased with.
It's a great shot from above here.
Look at that.
Even in slow motion, the divers hit the water fast, don't they?
It looks more than 30 feet, doesn't it, when they leap off the board like that?
I suppose when they're going up, it is more than 30.
It's 33 feet, isn't it?
Oh, yeah.
So technically, yeah.
Thank you, Mr. Pedant.
now and a pang of malaysia not going for the big stakes yet 2.9 back two and a half with pike oh beautiful
Cruising, opting for the back two and a half pike.
She could easily make back three and a half, but she's opting for the easier one.
Here we go, up into the pike shape, that beautiful pike shape, spotting the water, pointing her toes right down, making the dive look so beautiful and it works out for her.
In my opinion, that's worth a nine and that's a beautiful dive.
Now, let's see whether Leon's thoughts are transmitted to the judges on the far side have just inputted their scores.
Just coming up on the scoreboard to our right.
And come up on your scoreboard now on your screen.
75.409s are what she is given.
Kim Jin Ok of Korea.
It was Republic of Korea.
In with three and a half somersaults with Tuck.
Three point two for the young Korean.
Fourth after round one.
Well, she won't be fourth after round two.
Falling away from the diving board way too far there which makes it difficult.
It's almost like a trap door opened as
And there she goes, disappearing through the trap door, running out of room and then doesn't quite, she has two bites at the cherry as she tries to come out of the dive, straightening from the hips and then from the knees.
Yeah, the judges will go to town on that one and won't give her very good marks at all.
Went in a rather strange fashion there.
The knees were bent as she she went in.
Slightly rakish angle.
The judge is a bit in disagreement.
Two up to four point five on the screen there.
Only the top and bottom marks will count or won't count.
The middle ones that will.
Here comes Rivera off Cuba.
Such a shame.
She's got great aerial work She gets these dives moving and she doesn't seem to have very much an idea where she is Now that could be a big problem when you're diving you need to know pretty much exactly where you are proprioception and kinesthetic feedback ie where you are in relation to The water in this case.
Anyway, she's in and over lots of splash coming up and that puts her right at the bottom of the pack
If you haven't just tuned in, you're not listening to the Open University.
Those words suddenly come from heaven's sake.
Ah, they're real words.
You can look them up if you want, Bob.
Have you been reading a dictionary again?
Well, maybe.
Rivera, uh, 54.
The marks takes her to, uh, only 19th at the moment.
Uh, that's not gonna do it for her for qualification.
Tracy Tookiet of Malaysia, in with three and a half somersaults with Tuck, 3.2.
Oh over she goes we're going to see this a little bit the girls out there today they've got such complex dives to do and when you're doing such complex dives they can easily go wrong and Tracy here just unfortunately letting that dive go on the end there over you can see the splash going back
Almost said surfboards, which I think you might need to explain the drinking game, Bob.
There's some confusion.
I think there's some of my commentary fans out there have designed a drinking game with some of my more frequent sayings.
And I think get your surfboards out is one of them.
So I think that's a drink for those of you playing at home.
Have you ever been too tiddly by the end of this competition?
Now onto the American Katie Bell.
Now let's see what she does in terms of her preparation this time.
She's talking to herself, smiling to herself, and right old chatter.
I don't know what she's saying.
Is she going to count herself in again?
Yeah.
Yeah, she does.
There you go.
5, 6, 7, 8.
It's Sesame Street.
Oh, it's a difficult dive as well.
Reverse, two and a half, not in the tuck position, but in the pike position.
So it carries a higher degree of difficulty than the tuck position.
So it's 2.9.
I think it should be worth more than this 2.9 because that's really tricky.
You're jumping away, spinning backwards.
It makes me, well, shift in my chair every time I watch a diver perform this dive.
Katie just leaving it short there, running out of space to squeeze the dive in.
You can see the splash moving away from the diving board.
see the diver here moving the arms to the side with all that air coming down trying to you know cause that suction for the riff entry not quite working for Belle.
No she hasn't got it going yet five point fives higher six but that doesn't count and that's not the mark that she really wanted either from the first round or the second round she finds herself cast adrift in twenty first not seeing anything about Paola Espinoza Sanchez after putting the mouth on her in the first
Round so to speak.
Back three and a half sub assaults with tuck.
I think you're continuing to do that by just suggesting it, Bob.
She is all over the shop.
Wow.
I was watching her in training.
She looked on silver medal earlier this, well, last week now in the synchronized 10 meter.
And for a world medalist, this isn't very good at all.
The aerial works good and that is way over loads of splash.
She's only going to get fours at best.
Wow.
three dives to go.
I don't know whether that's too much to.
Well, no, I think she can come back but wow.
Yeah, she should be able to.
She's got some big dives still to come but twentieth place.
Not where we expected the bronze medalist from Shanghai to be at this stage of the competition.
That was only twelve months ago or so.
She won that bronze medal in the world championships.
Julia
Oh, she needed a ten and a half meter platform to get that dive in there.
This is the risk you run.
Bob and I have these conversations, why do some people go for the lower degree of difficulty?
Well, this is why, because the higher degree of difficulty carries so much risk.
There we go, just hitting the water up on the back, it feels like a bat around the back of the head as you go in there.
Oh, your shoulders are sore.
It's like a car crash.
Oh, being pulled to the side.
Well, she's made a tough stuff.
Doesn't seem to flinch, but that will hurt tomorrow morning for sure.
I think the marks will hurt more than the actual entry into the water.
I'm not sure.
Only forty seven point eight five for Poltanova.
Micagawa of Japan.
Going for a slight variance in what we've seen.
So this is a lot in the first round.
Other divers forward three and a half somersaults with Pike.
Beautiful rip entry into the water from Nakagawa.
They like it.
The fans, supporters and family here make shouting and screaming.
That's a very good dive.
Yeah, look at that pipe shape.
Her chin's almost on her ankles.
It's incredible the flexibility in some of these girls' spines and bodies.
Makes the dive very easy if you can get into a tight pipe shape and Nakagawa is certainly doing that with an entry to boot.
Backs up a 71.40 with a 72 and she goes on like that.
She'll be comfortably into the top 18 for the semi-final.
Well, the youngest competitor certainly showing her inexperience here today.
I was watching her in training and actually, you know, she's always going to struggle.
It's a big ask.
It's such a tender age to be coming into an Olympic Games and performing these dives and that's a
She's got an even more difficult one next round, so I'll be holding my breath when she does that one, hoping that she is okay.
And yeah, that isn't going to be good.
26th for Kim after the second round.
We've seen a lot of 4.5s today.
This is not going to help the progression of those who are looking for a top 18 place.
These are the divers who are very safe and with a bit of room for error.
Again, Benfeats is a good start.
Chen has, Melissa Wu, right down to nine, all in Reesbury comfortable territory.
And it gets a little bit tighter.
Up to eighteen, Arian, including Monique Gladding of Great Britain, Rosalind Philly on the last position at the moment.
And these are the ones on the next page who are going to have a little bit of work to do.
Right down to Stacey Powell in 25th.
And Kim of Korea in 26th.
Katie Bell, Stacey Powell, and Kim.
Passed the drift a little bit.
Not at three figures yet.
Stacey Powell is playing her dive in round three.
And here is round three of the Women's 10-meter platform preliminary.
Top 18 go through to the semifinal.
Top 12 then to the final.
At the moment, Brittany Viola is comfortable in sixth place.
After her first two rounds, she's going to go for an inward three and a half somersaults with Tuck in round three.
Start off the divers in this competition.
oh shame really all she needed to do was straighten out a little bit more she went into the water great britney says the banner not quite great enough on that dive
A real work is good.
Squeezing into that tuck shape quite near the diving board and then doesn't quite straighten out.
You can see the backside just poking out a little bit there.
If she'd have straightened out more, if she went in, she'd get more than sixes.
Six point fives.
Yeah, she would run in a little bit higher.
But again, preliminaries is just about making it through.
Hmm, Brittany.
Oh, baby, baby.
Sixes.
Fifty seven point six zero for Brittany Viola.
Audrey Lebeau of France, currently occupying 16th place, which will be good enough if she retains that for the next three rounds.
First of all, the armstands have been proving to be a little bit problematic so far in the competition, and she has hers right now.
Armstand back, double somersault, one and a half twists, 3.2 the degree of difficulty.
Oh, it's a good dive from Audrey, just over-rotating as she goes in.
And some of you may have seen, as Audrey was lifting up into the handstand, there was a technical official on the back of the 10-metre board.
There is a reason for this, because if the diver doesn't get up into the handstand successfully first time and they come down, that's a technical fault.
It actually becomes a restart.
So the technical official at the top of the 10-metre is there to make sure that the athlete does not restart.
It's an important part.
It's part of the FINA rules.
I know some of you have been questioning that, whether it's off-putting.
The technical official stands to the side out of the way.
I hope that explains that for everyone.
62.40 as we explain the marks for you.
Again, all the marks without lines through them count multiplied by the degree of difficulty.
And again Ben Fito has had a very good start.
Don't want to put the mouth on her eye there because they seem to have the commentators curse tonight.
In with three and a half somersaults.
Difficulty 3.2 for the first of the Canadians.
I think you should keep quiet Bob, I'll just do the commentary on my own otherwise we could see all sorts happening.
So Megan, first two dives as we mentioned, very good indeed.
Third round dive and I'm surprised because this one is actually normally pretty solid for it.
Yeah, she was another one who needed an 11 metre platform.
That's a real shame.
Lost it all on the takeoff.
Doesn't get enough spring.
Struggles on the rotation.
And then, yeah, the entry is impacted negatively.
It's all over when it started, actually.
I didn't realize I had that kind of influence but seemingly I do.
Fives on a three point two and that has taken her tumbling down the table but I think she's probably done enough in the first two rounds to have herself with a bit of a buffer, bit of a comfort zone margin for round five when we get to it.
Chain ruling.
World champion.
Second place after round two.
Yeah, no mistakes from Shenruling.
So experienced and this is very, very technically proficient.
Straight up and down right on the money.
Big scores coming her way.
One and a half twist straight down into the water.
Rip entry.
Nines.
8.5s at worst.
3.2 equals the lead.
I was going to have that uh ten meter ball measured on stage thinking it might be nine and a half or ten and a half.
It didn't seem to be working for everybody tonight but it's worked for her.
Eighty-one point six zero.
That takes her into uh quite a commanding lead.
Of course, the marks from the prelims are not carried forward to the semifinal.
Just a case of earning yourself a place.
Julia back two and a half.
Oh, she almost had it there.
It all looked good.
I think she just needed to lift her chin a little bit and look back at the water to glide that dive in.
She just doesn't look back far enough for me.
So instead of being completely upright, she's a little bit
well out of shape on the end on the end of the dive making much sense there but i think i will on this area i just needed to look back a little bit more to glide into the water with a slight back arch for eight so seven seemed a bit of a mixed bag from the judges
Sixty-five point two five for Pogupchuk.
Now, Stacey Powell needs all the support and all the help she can get from the home crowd because that second round dive not quite a drop dive.
In terms of marks, it wasn't quite what she wanted.
So, she hasn't got to the three-figure mark yet.
Ninety-six point nine zero after round two.
Can she repair some of that damage with a four, three and a half somersaults with Mike?
Yeah, she can repair the damage.
She's going to have to get her comeback claws out, dig them in, and pull herself back into contention.
The crowd's certainly like it.
They're looking for that rip entry, and there certainly was one on the end of that dive.
Little bit back from the end, and she is a little bit piped as she entered the water.
So I don't think she's going to get eights, but she certainly deserves 7.5s.
It's a real shame.
If she was completely straight on the entry into the water, then I think she should be getting nines.
It's a good dive from Stacey to pull her back into it.
Oh, good.
They've gone with a eight, well, 17, 17.5, but they don't count, so eight to count.
Yeah, 72, the total mark.
That will move her up a spot or two.
She needs to move up quite a few, though.
She has to get eight places to make that semi-final, but that is not beyond redemption.
Onto the diver with the Hungarian name, born in Hungary, but representing Italy.
Here's Naomi Bakke.
never been beyond the preliminaries in any major event so far could this be her turn back two and a half somersaults one and a half twists in the pike position
Well, it's her biggest dive.
I was watching her earlier, maybe suffering a little bit of injury.
Her coach was giving her a bit of a massage in between the shoulder blades.
The divers getting ripped here, there and everywhere as they enter the water.
If your head goes one way and your arm goes the other, it does feel like your shoulder's being dislocated.
There we are, putting themselves through all sorts of punishment to bring you the entertainment of the evening.
And that was good from the Italian.
Yeah, it's a pretty solid mark actually coming up on your screen.
67.20, certainly in the context of this competition.
If you're getting 67s most of the time, you'd be pretty happy because it would mean that you're going to make it through to the last 18.
She is on her way.
Christine Stoehrer of Germany in the preparation for that 3.2 degree of difficulty dive.
Arm stand back, double somersault, one and a half twists, you can hear the crowds in, take a breath can't you?
As I watch here, getting in the upright position on those heavily bandaged wrists.
Oh, wow.
She just seemed to fall off the diving board there.
Didn't even push with her hands.
Just seemed to use the momentum.
Falling is a very brightly colored costume, isn't it?
Making my eyes go a little bit a little bit funny.
Anyway, the dive is good.
Did she show control in the balance?
Maybe some of the judges will, you know, take some marks off for that.
Maybe just half a point.
Apart from not very much height from the hands is straight up and down.
She does a good job.
72 for Kristen Stewart.
Just examining the board, wondering what she could have done a bit better.
I think she can think about improving on that in the semi-final.
She may be on her way.
Now Monique Ladding is in 14th place after round two.
It's time for her arm stand.
And as ever with Monique, just taking a little bit of extra preparation time.
It's a dive that you've seen several times.
Arm stand back, double somersault, well and half twists.
That's an intricate and quite laborious preparation for Monique.
Wow, you could hear an absolute pin drop, couldn't you?
Monique, an ex-gymnast, from South Africa, coming in to her arm stand as if she's on the balance beam.
She comes in from the side.
It always scares me doing that.
I would never have got into my arm stand in that way.
She holds the arm stand beautifully, very steady, great home support, just a little bit of over-rotation.
Makes you get away with sevens.
Look at that, coming inside on as if she's on the balance beam.
but she's not.
She's perched on the end of the ten meter.
It's just such a strong jump.
Just giving it a little bit too much.
Revving the engine a little bit too hard over rotating.
So, congratulations from Melissa Wu there from Australia.
Girls are good friends.
Yeah, it's a fairly solid score though.
And in the context of this competition may well be good enough.
Mid-range score.
And the way things have been thus far mid-range score just about gets the job done.
Huyudan will replicate in terms of the dive we've just seen from Monique.
3.2 arm stand back double somersault, one and a half twists.
Oh, it's a good entry from Yudan.
However, she is tipping over a vertical.
Remember seeing her previous two dies, both of them a little bit off on the entries.
So we'll see.
Only very young, isn't she?
16.
I've seen her dive so much better than this.
I'm sure there's more to come.
I mean, she's going to get good marks on that.
But in training, I've seen this worth nines and tens, actually.
That's eight, maybe.
Yeah, eight.
That's all I go for on that.
Judges think.
Exactly the way you're thinking, pretty much.
And there was an 8.5, a slightly rogue one in there.
Eight otherwise.
And again, as we would expect, the Chinese are going to be there or thereabouts at the end of this competition.
Now to slightly more complicated arm stand back, triple somersault here for Kim of Korea.
Is Korea going to be over after this?
Ooh, over she goes.
Throwing up a lot of splash.
The lift into the arm balance, into the arm balance was absolutely superb.
Very gymnastic.
Showing very solid, good control.
And then flicks off, gets into the shape.
It's all looking good until there.
And then whoosh, there's a big tidal wave.
What a shame.
Look at the splash from this.
Whoosh, it's behind you.
the mark is forty-six point two zero.
We're gonna spread on that two point five up to five.
Five point five.
One of them two point five to five point five.
It's confused the judges that one.
That has more or less be fuddled.
Be fuddled.
Good words.
Yeah.
They couldn't work it out.
Hopefully they might do a bit better on Brittany Broban's arm stand.
I can't look at how there can be a three and a half point differential but we're revisiting old sores and old wounds aren't we on this one?
Arm stand back double somersault one and a half twists in case you're coming in fresh to the competition we've seen this a lot and this is the attempt by the sixteen year old Australian Brittany Brobin in round three
I'm impressed with this young lady, only 16 years old and she's holding it together, very composed.
Yeah, having a smile as well and good on you.
That's what it's all about.
Might as well have some fun.
This is what you do day in, day out, week after week, month after month, hour after hour.
Now's your time to shine and that's three out of three for the Aussie.
Yeah, sixty-eight, sixty-two and an eighty and they are happy with her and she will be happy with that.
And she goes up to two hundred and eleven and well on her way.
Three more rounds to go, of course.
Two more rounds to go after this.
Five in the women's, six in the men's.
Ronda Spaziani still not going for the high tariffs, still sticking in the twos.
2.9 for the Italian.
Back two and a half semisports.
Yeah, well, you enjoyed it.
It looked like she was conducting an orchestra then just before she took off.
But it's the arm swing that she chose to use and it seemed to be pretty effective.
Let's have a look at the takeoff.
We didn't get to see the arm swing then.
She's moving sideways a little bit.
A lot of arm movement there that she probably didn't need.
Bit of splash being thrown up.
Oh, big back arch as she takes off.
A little back arch as she goes in.
There we are.
But the problem's still on.
Maybe.
She she find a job there.
She doesn't qualify in here.
Fifty-two point two zero.
Give her a pass on.
She'll be well away.
Now on to Carolina Hernandez.
A back three and a half semisault with Tuck.
Right at the top of the degree of difficulty.
DD, which of course will be multiplied by the marks that she gets tenth after round two.
When you're ready.
oh she's having a big think about it wasn't she yeah people wondering well what you're taking so long for thinking it through and potentially that could be paralysis by analysis thinking too much trying too hard
Talked herself out of it.
There we go.
What a shame.
Kicking up towards the ceiling, which is way, way too late.
The takeoff was good.
Aerial work was good.
Staying on the diving board, I think a little bit too long.
Put herself off.
Talked herself out of it.
And now she's got some work to do, this young Mexican.
Is there an ideal length of time you take to do that?
Diver preference, you know, not too long.
And if you rush too much, you know, you need to give yourself time to be composed.
But I think that for me was potentially a little bit too long.
But then, of course, if she nailed it, I'd have to eat my words.
Thirty-nine point six zero though is not a great return on that dive for the length of time that she considered it.
Now to Roslyn Filion.
Eighteenth now, inward three and a half summer swaps with Tuck.
Three point two for the Canadian.
Oh, she's struggling a little bit today.
It's Alex and the rest of the Canadian contingent there cheering her on but she certainly needs to lift her game.
That's a poor second round dive and a poor third round dive.
Certainly for this young lady's standards.
She might get five and a halfs and sixes on this one but after a poor second round dive, it would need to be better.
That's a super slow motion.
Yeah, she's a safe distance from the diving board but not a
Yeah, not quite sure what's going on today.
A lot of missed dives or dives are very much on the par.
Sixes they give the judges and that's not going to help her status a great deal.
She was 18th after the previous round.
Lying on others to falter here.
Melissa Wu and her back three and a half.
We're tucked again.
We've seen it before.
We'll see how she performs.
Oh, that was all going a little bit askew on the takeoff there.
Moving too far away from the diving board, not quite getting her arms through on the takeoff and having a little bit of trouble to rotate.
Here we go.
Look.
Yeah, needed to reach up a little bit more before she came into a shape.
She was always running out of room.
She does an okay job of getting into the water there, but you can see her turning, turning into a little bit of a banana as she went in.
Needs to be straight and vertical as you go in, not with a big back arch.
Well, that would hurt if she went in.
Hopefully, she's okay.
You're onto the shots now.
That was a banana reference.
Sixty-two point seven zero for Melissa Wu and at the moment with quite a few times to go.
She's holding her back to Chava, the coach going, ow, hurt myself as I went in.
She's into third.
Has a bit of a back injury to think about as she goes into round four.
Here's Kyo of Germany.
Inward two and a half.
Oh, that's her best dive out of the three so far from Maria.
Easiest dive.
Two point eight degree of difficulty.
So, she knows that she needed to make it count and she certainly has.
Oh, maybe touching the toes on the diving board there.
These girls, it's often the case and even with two and a half in the pike position.
Does she do it?
Will it stay with this shot?
Oh no, she just, oh, a toenail away with her toenails.
She's glad she cut them this
seven point five eight seven point five they count towards the score of sixty four point four zero remember all the marks with lines through them do not count top and bottom discarded the middle three added up with the degree of difficulty as you can see in that shot we are in arm stand territory again
It's at 3.2 again and it's the back double somersault, one and a half twists.
A crowd like me can take a breath.
Oh, she's overcooked it.
She cranked it up on the start and gave it a bit too much.
So diving is about being precise.
And she just gets after the dive a little bit too aggressively.
Doesn't have time to, you know, to slow it down.
There's nothing she could do there.
She was always going to over-rotate on that.
Needed to flick up a little bit more with the feet rather than flicking down, increasing the rotation.
Nothing she could do there.
Mistake on the takeoff, over-rotation on the end.
Well, we've talked up a lot of the competition so far.
I'd say I think this is a little bit of a below par prelims to be honest.
But we're waiting for somebody to really bring it to life and to light up the board.
Here comes Kim of Korea.
Back three and a half somersaults with Tuck.
3.3 degree of difficulty.
Let's hope that she is a substantial distance away from the board.
Some of the competitors have been getting a little bit too close for comfort.
Oh, she's done a really good job there.
I was looking at Bob there, giving him the sign for this could go either way.
I've been watching this in training.
I'm not sure whether she's going to nail this one or whether she could go crashing into the water as I watched her do just before this contest started.
Anyway, Kim nailing her biggest dive when it counts.
They're back three and a half.
She plays the waiting game, pops her feet up directly towards the ceiling.
She'll get herself some good marks on that one.
a little bit further up and in contention for a top eighteen spot.
Yeah.
At the moment, 70s are a very good score.
You're getting 70s.
You are moving up the pecking order.
You know, starting to get yourself in contention because there's been so many forties and I remember that score.
A few people are
Oh, I don't think that's going to get out the 20s.
Yeah, just showing you how difficult diving is.
Now, let's be fair, we are at the Olympic Games and watching the best of the best.
And when you do it so well, it almost looks easy.
But let me tell you, it's far, far from easy.
And this is an example how easy it can go wrong.
You've only got 1.6 seconds to get your dive in.
In this case, not get it in.
Two point fives from Fred and the way things are panning out, she will not be returning for the semifinal.
So there are so many calamities today you can't predict at this stage.
Tracy Turkett of Malaysia playing a little bit more safe with a two point nine.
Back two and a half somersaults with Pike.
Twenty first at the moment and not returning as things stand for the semis.
just a little bit over.
Watch the diver Anya before her and go very very short of vertical using the same dive or opting for the same dive.
Tracy decides to hang on just a touch longer than she needs to.
Reaching over, just tipping over a vertical.
Four and a half fives.
Yeah, she'll be way off the pace as well.
Quite close to those rings as well.
They're a good marker for you.
See how far they are away from the board if they're landing in the rings, and she very nearly did.
Tracy took it.
It's not going to help her cause a great deal.
47.85.
Now, I'm intrigued by the build up to this dive from Katie Bell.
Let's be quiet for a second, Bob.
She's making an old chat to herself, isn't she?
In with three and a half.
Take it away Katie.
Oh, and it certainly worked this time.
One, two, three, go, is what you heard from a young Miss Belle.
And then away she went.
Steve Foley, National Performance Director, watching on from the audience there.
And Belle, this is the dive of her meet.
And look at that wicked entry into the water.
Super slow motion, safe distance from the diving board.
It's a big dive, difficult to make, and she disappears into the water.
Good work.
Hurrah.
We've got a dive to save her at last, and she has two after a couple of not great rounds.
That's much, much better.
78.40, and she's given herself a chance up into 15th now.
I am saying nothing about this diver, apart from what she's going to do.
It's a reverse three and a half somersaults with tuck, 3.3 degree of difficulty for the top ranked Mexican.
Well, she dives a lot better when you don't say anything.
Well, she's the only lady to choose to use this dive.
It is incredibly difficult.
Well, the degree of difficulty is 3.3, and that's too low for this dive.
It used to be 3.4, and then Fina messed around with the degrees of difficulty, and this dive suffered.
It's much more difficult than the back three and a half.
It is the reverse three and a half, normally seen only in the men's competition.
Paola just showing her, well, amazing dynamic diving style, and that's her best dive, and she needed it.
72.60.
She does it best when I say nothing at all.
Now, on to Yulia Koltanova of Mexico.
Sorry, of Russia.
She's moved a bit.
Four, three and a half somersaults, pike.
Oh, it's steady.
She had a poor second man dive, didn't she?
This young lady.
So, it needed to be good.
Quite a few girls with a bit of work to do.
And this young lady coming out on her third round with a forward three and a half.
It's a good pike shape.
Oh, looks good to hear.
Just maybe a touch shorter vertical but still, if it gets over 70 points, there are the judges looking on with the devices in the hands ready to input the scores and they
for the Russian diver.
Now, Nagagawa of Japan.
That score by the way was 73.50 for Colton over.
On to the back three and a half for the
Oh, what a big dive.
This is the hardest that she's going to perform.
Back three and a half.
You've seen lots of the girls faltering on this one.
Many of them choosing the easier backward two and a half in the pipe position.
Nakagawa really going out on this one.
Has to squeeze in.
Her hands are a bit high in that tuck shape, close to the knees.
She does okay, but she seems to bend her knees as she goes in, which gives the impression she was short, but when she wasn't.
So, moving her feet too early.
Look, as she goes in, just collapsing a little bit on entry which is a shame.
Yeah, it doesn't back up the seventy-one point four and the seventy-two for Nakagawa.
Sixty-six for the Japanese but things are okay for her in terms of being back for the semi.
She's in quite safe territory in sixth at the moment.
Now, Kim of Korea finally in this round.
Oh, you know, I was watching this in training and I was hoping it would be better than training, but that's exactly what she's been doing in training.
She's only 14 years old.
She's in the Olympic Games and actually these dives are a little bit too difficult for her.
She shouldn't really be doing these dives until she's more proficient at the lower level.
Look at that.
She's very lucky not to really hurt herself there.
That's only going to get, well, twos maybe.
She must have hurt herself, sure.
Yeah, but she could have really hurt herself.
And look, she's she swam to the side.
She's OK. Yeah.
Coach is saying you should.
Well, I'm not sure what he's saying, but well, a pride will certainly be hurt if her body is not for those marks that have come up on the screen.
Three, two point five and two will count towards her score of twenty four point seven five.
So the end of round three.
Women's 10 meter platform.
Chinese one and two.
No real surprise there.
The Australian three and four.
Likewise, all of those on that front page are feeling okay about themselves.
As far as Monique Gladding is concerned, she has a little bit of a buffer there, 19 points away from problems.
But look at Paolo Espinosa-Sanchez, bronze medalist from last year in 18th place.
Hanging on by fingernails, Stacey Powell has made up a bit of ground.
She was 25th, she's now 21st after round three.
Ladies and gentlemen, please welcome the President of the United States of America
Round four, about to start.
With the women's it's four rounds, then five.
And then with the men, it's five rounds and six.
So we also have that extra round for the men before we get to the conclusion of their program.
We'll see later on in the week.
For the women it's five.
And the degree of difficulty is not quite as high.
Stacey Powell waiting for her turn for Great Britain.
And first up, not the best position.
And we're going to have a change of judges.
After three rounds, we changed the people with the devices.
Didn't think they all came from Wiltshire.
Oh, it's devices.
Here they are.
My favorite judge is back.
Hannah Navotna is just one letter away from being a Wimbledon champion.
So just to remind you how the judges work, all seven judges input their scores into the score pad and the device they hold in their hands.
Those seven scores are calculated or actually brought together.
The two highest and two lowest are discounted.
They will be shown with the lines through them.
The three that count are multiplied by the degree of difficulty, which gives the total for that particular dive.
First diver in round four of the Women's 10 meter platform preliminary is from the USA and is Brittany Viola and she will perform a slightly lower tariff diver, slightly lower though, 2.9 degree of difficulty on this back, two and a half somersaults performed in the pike position.
Oh, it's a good dive from Brittany.
Opening up three good ones already in the bag and then this one just a little over as she goes into the water, backwards spinning.
So, you can only see where you've been, not where you're going.
So, has to judge where to point her feet at.
Just miss timing it there slightly.
Means it over.
She goes.
She'll get sixes.
She wanted more than that.
Her program is rather tailed off, isn't it?
But so good scores of seventy and seventy-three and then fifty-seven followed by fifty-three.
Uh she's starting to just hurtle down the top eighteen standings but she was eighth after round three.
So, should be okay.
Providing nothing untoward happens later on.
Audrey Lebeau of France for three and a half
Just getting into the realms of threes now.
3.0 exactly on her dive number four.
Oh wow.
Some faults starting to come in now.
It's very difficult to hold your concentration on such a long competition.
Remember each dive takes around 1.6 seconds and then you go and sit down for 20 minutes or so in between dives and then need to get yourself back in the game and Audrey there faltering over a vertical.
Lots of splash being thrown up.
Wow, that'll put her off the pace.
This pack is really being shuffled right before her eyes.
That's why it's difficult really to write anybody off at this stage because who gets themselves into a good position and then immediately undoes all the good work.
Forty point five zero Audubon.
That's not going to help.
Sixteenth after round three, probably outside the top eighteen after this.
armstand time for Megan Benfito 3.3 degree of difficulty attached to this one.
It's an armstand back triple somersault with tuck
Oh, everyone's having a go.
Maybe I'm not sure what's happening out there.
You can tell by the swim to the side that she does not want to come up and hear the scores.
All looks okay so far.
And then just thinking she's rotating slower than she is, so pointing her toes up a little bit too high.
Misjudging.
Ending over a vertical, mixed bag.
It's a shame it's 3.3 and that isn't going to count really, the degree of difficulty.
You need more raw scores, more execution marks from the judges.
5.5 isn't going to cut it.
Any obvious reason why the standard tonight isn't really not kind of good off base level, is it, at any stage?
bit unfair to some of the divers who have had a little bit of brilliance and as we move on to the Olympic champion, let's see if she can buck the trend.
General in back three and a half somersaults.
Let's see how it should be done from the Chinese.
Well, it was good.
It was better than what we have been seeing, but it's not of the standard of the Olympic champion that we would be accustomed to.
It's a big dive there.
It's 3.3.
Let's not take away on how difficult it is.
And up until this point, it's perfect.
Just a little bit over as she goes into the water.
It's going to get over 70 points.
And in women's platform diving, over 70 points is very good.
And sometimes we see them get over 80 as well.
Well, she did in the previous round.
Eighty-one point six zero but this time round nowhere near as good.
A high tariff too.
Seventy-four point two five.
But no doubting that she'll be in the top eighteen come the end of this competition.
Equal fourth going into round four.
And again, that's the arm stand.
Again, it's worth 3.3.
OK, let me explain what she's done there.
And this is why we have the official at the back of the diving board to see if this happens.
So this is actually a restart.
So she's gone to lift up into the handstand.
She is overbalanced, and she's come down.
Now, what will happen is she will perform the dive.
The judges will mark out of 10, as normal.
But then there will be a two-point deduction from each judge for the restart.
So I'll explain that when the marks come up, so she has to compose herself, forget that she's just made a glaring error, and go.
Oh, what a shame.
All she needed to do was lift her chin as she went back into the water and that would have been spot on.
Well, nothing you can do about the restarts for the judges as I explained.
Well, Mark had a ten.
There will be a two-point deduction from each of the judges and then it will be multiplied by the degree of difficulty to give the total.
So, it's a shame the dive wasn't a little bit better for her.
She did all the hard work.
and then she needed to look back a little bit more with her chin to get upright as she went into the water let's have a look so she would have got seven reads five seven and a half reads five and a half and seven and a half reads five and a half to give the total of 52 yeah she knows there's not much you can do there's no point the coach telling her she knows exactly what she had to do and what she didn't do
Crowd really getting behind Stacey Powell, who's done a little reparation job in round three.
Still a little bit more to do.
But as you can see, everybody else faltering.
She has a chance to take advantage of that with a 3.2.
Inward three and a half somersaults with Tuck.
Very talented young diver when she came through at Crystal Palace.
and has moved on in leaps and bounds and I can she do it literally with this fourth round dive, Stacey Powell.
Oh, she needed to be better than that.
Very poor second round dive and just off the game here.
Real shame.
I was standing up and clapping this dive in training which was, you know, just 10 minutes before the start of this competition here.
Staying in the tuck shake too long.
Chin in on the chest.
Look at all that splash being thrown up.
Well, there's been lots of divers who are making mistakes and
One more dive to go and that would need to be nailed in order for her to get through.
48 I'm afraid.
That's a sorry tale for Stacey.
Fives ending up to 48 so she's at 29 and a 48.
That could ultimately be the difference between her getting through to the semi-final and not.
Badki of Italy with an inward three and a half in the tuck position.
Well, this is Naomi's most difficult dive and she has certainly turned it on when it counts.
Watching lots of her competitors falter around her, knows if she wants to make it through, this most difficult dive of hers needed to be good and that will get seven and a halfs and eights maybe and a big score.
Judges just inputting their scores into their machines.
And this is what they say.
Seven point five and eight for Naomi Bakke.
And seventy five point two and she's been one of the most consistent divers here tonight.
Hasn't been below sixty five in any of the rounds.
Christian Stewart of Germany, twelfth after round three.
So back two and a half some of it again but um degree of difficulty down below the threes into two point nine.
It's normally one of her better dives and it proves the same today.
Very consistent on this backwards spinning move.
Seems to know exactly where she is.
Spotting the water twice as she spins around.
Showing the strain on the takeoff there.
This will get eight and a halfs for sure.
It's a beautiful dive.
Reaches back in looking for that rip entry and there it is.
Well, there you go, underlining why sometimes the lower tariff dives have a safety first option.
And she just proved it with a 2.9 where the 3.3s haven't been working for others.
She picks up a nice, decent, solid score.
And she can jog her weight into the top 18 fairly soon with dives like that.
73.95.
Monique and then a good reaction, a good support, and a good reception from the home crowd and she performs with come on Monique from uh somebody in the crowd.
She's trying to compose herself.
There you are.
You get an idea just what she has to do and where she has to go.
Fantastic shot.
That's it.
Back two and a half somersaults with Pike.
Two point nine.
Monique.
Just getting the breathing right.
Getting the posture right.
Fourteenth.
After round three.
Oh, she's let it go as well.
It's a real shame.
The takeoff look good.
She has been struggling with a neck injury.
Maybe that was she's protecting it a little bit.
She didn't look back as she came out.
Seemed to stay in a slight dish position letting the dive go over.
Oh, just overcooked it.
Over she goes and that's oh poor dive for Monique as well.
Has she done enough?
One more dive to go and
Well, first three round dives were okay, so she's got a little bit of margin for error.
39.15 will pull it back a little bit.
And she was 14th after round three, so it's tight for qualification.
Hu Yidan of China, third after round three.
Wow, everyone's having a go at making mistakes this evening, just showing you how difficult it is to perform consistently in this level of competition.
Lots of divers, lots of waiting in between dives and some lapses in concentration, even from who you're done.
Well, short as she goes in, throwing up the splash, maybe, I know, four and a half, five.
How are you going to get about 50 points?
I'm really, really puzzled by this.
Espinosa having an off night, you and Dan having a bit of an off night.
It's kind of who wants to grab this competition.
I know that the marks won't be carried forward but you've got to get in that top eighteen.
She should have a bit of a safety buffer anyway but it's amazing.
The best divers in the world not coming to terms with this competition so far with a few notable exceptions.
Kim Won Hyang with her back three and a half somersaults with tuck.
Big degree of difficulty for her.
3.3 get it right and she will go leaping up the standings and into the top 18.
Oh get it right she does there we go bucking the trend once again one or two divers refusing to fall in rapport with all the others who seem to be faltering left right and centre.
Kim here absolutely nailing her back three and a half that's really good that should get close to 80 points and that's going to be one of the highest scoring dives of the competition so far.
Well, it can be done and she has just done it.
79.20 is on my screen with confirmation on yours.
There it is.
Eight times the degree of difficulty and 240.90 and she's within touching distance of returning tomorrow morning.
Brittany Broben back three and a half for her.
3.3 in the tuck position.
Oh, it's her most difficult dive and a lot of girls faltering on this one.
Brittany there, the young 16 year old holding it together.
It's not the best she's ever done it.
I've watched her in training, but she's got such power.
Look at that double almost by board level.
She knows where she is.
Just moving her feet a little bit too high but yeah, that's going to get high 60s which is good enough especially in this level of contest.
You can afford not to dive at your best and still make it through effortlessly.
You know, I think the judges are actually quite happy to see a dive.
They can give some marks so maybe they get a little bit more than it deserved but seventy point nine five is okay.
That's very good by the standards of tonight and she will go
and up there with the best.
Brenda Spaziani of Italy.
Arm stand back, double sub-assault, one and a half twist, 3.2 degree of difficulty we've already seen.
Now this can go wrong and the effort you have to be put through and go through is going to be precise.
Well, Brenda seemed okay all the way through that dive and then just couldn't seem to hold the splash down as she went in.
The dive's a little bit maybe aggressive on the start.
A little bit too much rotation means the over-rotation in the entry.
Here you go, can't quite stop it.
And then the splash rolls over.
Another mediocre dive.
Very ordinary dives here this evening for a lot of the women.
What do the judges rate or reckon to that?
They rate it very highly at all.
Five point fives and a five.
A four right at the end but that won't count.
And that's a mark.
And Spaziani won't be overly encouraged by.
Fifty-one point two zero for the Italian.
Now on to Carolina Hernandez of Mexico.
Joint
in a long preparation before she lifts off with an inward three and a half somersaults with tuck and three point two is the degree of difficulty on this one.
Oh, she's having to dig deep.
to get herself back in contention and that will certainly help.
3.2 degree of difficulty.
A real shame on her previous dives.
She made a real mess of it this one.
Fortunately she's back in the kind of form she's been showing in training.
Only 15 years old.
Mexico riding high from recent successes.
and Hernandez here trying to get back in contention.
I think that might help.
Well, it's not going to hinder her after some of the marks we've seen.
Yeah, I think in the seven point five range is pretty good by tonight's standards.
Seventy-two for her.
That's why the smile is back on the face.
She contemplates hopefully being back in the top eighteen for the semifinal.
Now, Roslyn Filion
Arm stand back triple somersault.
Way too close to the exclusion zone at the moment.
3.3.
The degree of difficulty is slightly more difficult arm stand than the previous one.
Oh, she's nailed it and she needed to.
again faltering on the second and third round dives here's their fourth round dive the highest equal highest degree of difficulty 3.3 so tricky balancing her hand she's quite high on her tuck shape she does manage to dig her fingernails into the top of her knees there and hang on in there for the ride and she makes it mid 70s and that will certainly move her up the field
Yeah, she'll be much happier with that after a couple of dives.
I haven't quite gone her way.
That one definitely does.
And the mark of seventy five point nine zero lifts her up the standings and she can start to think one more dive and hopefully I will be safe for tomorrow.
But nobody the ten downward stage can really be thinking that right now.
Melissa Wu in with three and a half somersaults for the Australian.
Over she goes.
Hard work done.
Aerial work is good and then just the exit from the dive she isn't.
predicting it correctly either seeing the water at the right time is a real shame because it all looks good so far and then she just mistimes that entry and over she goes splash throws back towards the diving board and even Melissa Wu having a wobble out there 54.40 and the top marks are eluding many of the top divers
That's how it stands at the moment.
Chen, Robin and Baki.
There's still quite a few names to go.
Next up will be Maria Coyo of Germany from Berlin.
And it's a back two and a half somersaults, one and a half twists for her.
Yeah, it's okay.
She seemed to get it all working in the right way in the end.
some interesting movements before she took off but got there in the end here we are one and a half twist a little bit low on the water here but she plays the waiting game looks at the water punches a hole with her hands and gets in relatively clean not so much splash
pretty average mediocre ordinary six is six point fives don't really know i've got a word that i can use for that but there we go it's hard to know what is mediocre today though isn't it 62.40 for the gem and that might just be good enough to slider up the standings and get her on the cusp of making the top 18
On to the Malaysian.
Pandela Pang.
Tucked position for the inward three and a half.
Tenth after round three.
Oh she's on fire today.
One of the few that are actually performing.
Look at that punch in the air from the Malaysian coach.
He likes it and I certainly do.
Thank you.
It's nice to see some well executed dives and this from Pandela.
Superb.
Will it get over 80 points and wake up the competition a little bit and keep me?
It needs it.
Keep me on the edge of my seat.
It needs shaking up.
Grabbing the hands, punching a hole in the water, taking all the all the air down with her, causing a suction, excuse me, for that rip entry.
I think it's about the fourth eighty of the night.
So I'm at four for fifths.
There haven't been too many more than that.
Eighty one point six zero for Panda.
Yeah, we've been sleeping too.
Here's Kim Jin Ok. Arms down for her.
Kicking the board.
Yeah, using an incredible amount of arm strength there.
Very gymnastic on her approach and the technical takeoff.
Here we go.
Look at this.
Looks like a vault.
Oh, she did.
She actually put her nose on the platform.
Wow, that can't be very comfortable.
I wouldn't like to bang my nose on the platform before I then flick off with the legs.
Here we are.
She pops up one, twisting in.
Very peculiar and uncomfortable, I would suggest.
But there we go.
The dive was all right.
No bruise on the nose that I can see.
And 65 points to take away with her.
Well, obviously, in your case, it would improve it.
But 65.10 for Kim.
And she's up to 12.
Anya Rivera of Cuba her turn to do the 3.2 version 3.3 version 3.2 version of the arm stand back a double somersault one and a half twists.
This is it.
That's one of her better dives today.
Really struggling out there today.
The young Cuban.
And it's nice to see her land in the water without hurting herself.
The previous dive would have caused her some discomfort, that one on her head.
But yeah, she'll be one of the few.
I think the eight that won't be going through into the top 18.
And she'll be one of them.
Fives and one six.
Total mark 54.40.
Tracy Turkiet of Malaysia.
And looks like she's on her way through.
Unfortunately at the moment Tracy is not.
2.7 we're right down the bottom of the scale here.
Reverse two and a half.
It's well executed.
As Bob was suggesting she is off the pace at the moment.
Only 24th after the previous round.
Probably needed to be a little bit better on this, although it is one of her better efforts.
Reverse two and a half, standing forwards, jumping away from the diving board, spinning backwards towards it.
It'll get sevens, seven point fives maybe.
It's low DD, so probably won't get too close to, well, close to sixty.
Pretty much on the button there, Leon.
Sixty point seven five for Tracy.
Seven point fives.
And that's better, but not quite good enough.
Alright.
Breath.
Just a swimsuit.
Talk to yourself.
Have a chat.
Then count yourself in.
Back three and a half somersaults for Katie Bell, the twenty-four-year-old.
What kind of counter we're going to get this time?
oh it's a good dive the five six seven eight counting certainly worked for this time yeah it seems to be very fidgety but um quite a nervous looking character on the end of the diving ball but if any of you sitting at home are up on the 10 meter i'm sure your heart would be beating
a little bit quicker than normal normally and Katie Bell there nailing her fourth round dive backing up the third round Diver room with three and a half with a back three and a half this is her highest degree of difficulty and she's made it count they shall shoot her up the leaderboard yeah five six seven eight taking steps to put things right 79.20
Onto the bronze medalist from last year at the World Championships.
We haven't seen that kind of form so far and she is flirting with going out 18th place.
Are we going to see the real Paula Espinosa Sanchez on this dive in with three and a half somersaults 3.2.
Well, that's much more like it.
That is a nod towards the real Pola Espinoza Sanchez.
Silver medalist with a partner in the synchronized platform.
She was diving a lot better in the synchronized platform.
Of course, this is more like it.
Little over a vertical but that'll get eight mid 70s again to go with the seventy-two from the third round and I think she's back approaching the uh the top end of the
the top ten.
Well, it's only lifted her up a few places for the time being up to 13th from 18th and that will be secure.
Of course, you can start all over again in the semis if she does make it.
Yulia Koltanova, ninth at the moment.
Two more dives for her to come and it's the inward three and a half somersaults.
Tuck position.
3.2 is the degree of difficulty.
She's just over the 200 mark.
Oh, she's a little low on the water but managed to get out of it just in time to give the impression that she was vertical as she went in.
The judges will take marks off for her being a low finish.
Oh, it's a little close to the diving board.
Yeah, it's a little bit over with an arch as well.
I don't know.
I don't know what I'd give that actually.
A little bit close, a little bit low, six and a half maybe.
I don't know.
I didn't really like it that much.
Judges being a bit generous perhaps 7.5 will count as well as seven on your screen lines through the scores mean they do not count multiplied by the degree of difficulty 70.40 is how you arrive at that mark.
Mai Nakagawa of Japan 2.9 but she's already done some good work to get herself in sixth place with two more dives for her to go.
over a vertical throwing up a load of splash up until that point my Nakagawa had been very very steady and very solid whilst those around her were faltering she seemed to be unwavering but this one a little bit wavy and there's a wave as she goes in throwing up a load of splash that's a great shot isn't it super slow-mo London 2012
Maya Maya, give us a wave.
Not with those scores.
5.5 and 47.85.
Again, he sounds I said that not what she would have wanted.
It's almost like passing the baton, right?
I'm not done very well.
Your turn now.
Kim Suji.
It's a round things off.
Reverse two and a half semisault.
Oh, that's her best dive.
Wow!
Maybe you heard it, I took a sharp intake of breath as she took off.
I wasn't sure which way up she was going to land or whether her feet were going to come close to the diving board.
which they do a little bit.
She hangs on in there squeezing in and then, yep, she plonks it on her head safely and securely for her best dive of this contest.
Sadly, she had so much ground to make up.
She actually hasn't made up any ground at all in terms of position because she was twenty-sixth.
She is twenty-sixth.
But good.
Much better.
Brought the smile back to her face and
end of round four.
Bit of a shake up in that round, wasn't it?
Chen from Broban.
Pang up to third.
You know, the Chinese Hugh is down to sixth.
So, two sixty-four in ninth place.
Who's in 18?
Hernandez in 18.
None of the Brits in the top 18 at the moment.
How much do they have to do to make up the ground?
Are they cast to drift or can they repair the damage?
It's going to take a lot.
Monique Ladding in 20th place and Stacey Powell in 22nd.
Anybody pretty much below that is out of the competition.
Well, while the standard of the men's three-meter last night was exemplary, we're kind of waiting for this competition to come to life.
It hasn't done yet, but there's so much still to be done and so many twists and turns.
in the last round and still a lot of places to be gained and a lot of places to be lost.
Top eighteen, remember, the twelfth as Brittany Viola is and she is safe but she's got to finish off her program and underline that fact.
We've had all the other range of dives from her and to finish off the program it's a back two and a half somersaults, one and a half twists with Pike, three point two.
Can she finish off in style?
Oh, yes, she can.
Very, very good entry into the water.
However, I think she's over twisted.
Let's look at the replay.
The judges, well, if they spot it, they should penalize for that.
The divers should be square side on as you go in.
There we are rocking and rolling a little bit and I can see both ankles and both calves as she went in.
That means that she's over twisted.
So the judges could look at that rocking and rolling.
Not in a good way, though, like driving an out of control bus, but she manages to square it up.
That's good.
322.
Touched with the chubby checkers there, but she gets away with it.
Sevens for Brittany Viola, and she will be returning in the semifinals.
not a statement I can make at the moment about Audrey Lebo.
She could.
Back two and a half somersaults, one and a half twist, twenty-first, three point two degree of difficulty for the French woman's final dive.
Oh, I don't think she'll be coming back with that.
Oh, definitely not.
In fact, if she was in twenty-first place, which is what the
Blown dive to finish.
Bit of a shambles.
Oh, what a shame.
Short.
Low scores.
Oh, disappointing end.
Come on.
I thought we were going to get a finish with a flourish.
It's not happening for Miss LeBeau.
A bag of oats for Mr. Taylor while we're at it.
36.80 for Audrey LeBeau.
Now, Megan Benfito next, 14th.
A lot of Canadian support, both in the crowd, I know watching on TV as well.
As she performs her back, two and a half somersaults, one and a half twists, pike position 3.2, just to confirm her semi-final place.
Finally, someone who wants to get in the final, someone who wants to make it through, almost unscathed from this prelim.
Not a great day for Megan, some good stuff and then some very mediocre stuff from this already Olympic bronze medalist from last week.
It's a solid finish though, that'll get over 70 points and through she goes.
Yep, puts the top of the pile for the time being.
That's a qualification well and truly achieved.
Coach Happy, she should be too.
And all the things she got wrong tonight, she can rectify again in the morning.
Chen Ruolin, Olympic and world champion.
In position number one, as you might expect, for somebody with those accolades.
Back two and a half somersaults, one and a half twists to finish.
Yep.
No mistakes all night from Sherry Lynn.
Although she hasn't been top of the game, she hasn't really needed to.
She is head and shoulders and miles out in front of everyone else.
She should be a clear victor by well over 50 points.
One and a half twist, two and a half somersaults.
Vertical entry, hardly any splash.
Well, you can see why she's Olympic and world champion.
Olympic champion only fifteen.
She's now grand old age of nineteen.
And she'll be tough to beat.
She is currently not only number one but sixty-seven points ahead of Megan Benfito.
That's how much better she has been diving than the top Canadian at the moment.
Ninth after round four.
Trying to line her transition into the last eighteen.
Back two and a half somersaults, one and a half twists.
You've seen it before.
Here it comes again.
oh she's she's done some fantastic dives and that one isn't one of them unfortunately hard work had been done just making a a bit of a misjudgment on the finish one and a half twist into the two and a half somersault stretches forward too far ends up short and under twisted so she'll get sixes and six point fives to deliver disappointing finish for this young girl here
Yes, there we are.
I can see both anchors again.
The judges may even peep while they've gone with her.
It's okay.
Yeah, total mark.
60.80 and 324 will be enough to see her through now.
Stacey Powell.
proud doing everything they can to lift her.
First of the British competitors.
But this has to be her best dive of the night by some way or else this will be the end of Stacey's competition.
Four places outside qualification and the marks are there for her if she can get this right.
Back two and a half somersaults, one and a half twists, reasonably high degree of difficulty.
Very high, three point two for Britain's Stacey Powell.
Oh, that's more like it.
She really, really needed to pull it out the bag.
And she has.
Now, will it be enough?
I'm not sure.
It's a really, really good dive.
It's going to get eights.
It may even get 8.5s.
Is the entry clean enough to get eights from the judges?
It's 3.2.
I've seen it much better than this.
Just throwing up a little bit too much, plus maybe the judges won't go with it.
Finally, she does a dive that she's capable of, but I think she might have left it too late.
Too much to do.
Yeah, I'm not sure the mark that's coming up here is going to be good enough.
Seventy point four zero.
She didn't get the eights you needed on the eight point fives.
The seven point fives will accrue and Stacey, I'm afraid it looks like you will not be returning in the semifinals, but there's still some room for other things to go wrong.
Naomi Bakke.
It's two point seven lowest degree of difficulty we've seen.
Reverse two and a half.
Oh, faltering on a final dive.
Her lowest degree of difficulty.
She was way up there in the top end of the field, right in the business end of the field.
And now she has, well, saved her worst for last, unfortunately.
Here we go.
The takeoff is good.
This is her best dive normally, but she kicks out way too late, way over.
Look at that tidal wave.
Surfboard moment.
Have a drink on us, boys.
44.554, bat key.
and well she may already have done enough anyway not to have to be too concerned about that last round dive but she would want to finish with a flourish and she hasn't kristin stir after a great start has gone into a stride and she will go for a forward three and a half somersaults with pike
Oh, superb rip entry into the water.
Vertical, splashless, and that's going to get some good marks from the judges, even though her takeoff is a little bit weak.
She's not the most powerful of the women here, finishing a little bit low on the water, but that will get eights, I'm sure, because of that superb entry.
That's the best dive we've seen from Kristen this evening, and she'll secure a place in the semi-final effortlessly with that one.
Yeah, she had a very poor start, 51.80, but then 72, 72, 73 and a 72.
And yes, Smarr can remain there for a bit longer.
I guess she will be returning.
Now Monique.
20th position after round four.
She has a few points to make up.
Of course, the equation is if she does, it's like she has done it and can do it.
It's forward three and a half somersault.
Could be her passage into the last 18.
3.0 degree of difficulty.
She needs to be looking for 7080 marks really.
To put her there.
Oh yeah, it's straight up and
So will it be good enough?
Will it be good enough?
The crowd are expecting.
The crowd are wanting.
So she was in 20th after the previous round.
It's only 3.0 degree of difficulty.
That's a good dive to finish on.
She's clean into the water.
She probably needs more than sevens and 7.5s.
I think that's what she's going to get with that effort and she will have an agonising weight now looking at the scoreboard to see whether her total score which will be on your screen shortly is good enough to secure a spot in the top 18.
Well she's gone over 300 which is encouraging.
67.50 is quite encouraging.
but it's margins, it's fractions, and it could be very, very tight still.
She's giving herself a chance.
Hu Yudan of China.
Back two and a half sevensaults, one and a half twists to finish with pike position for the second ranked Chinese.
And she's been very mediocre today.
Now, the Yudan is normally something quite special.
I would expect her to see her up, pushing her teammate, Shen Ru Lin, but she's been way off the pace today, only in sixth after the fourth round of dives.
I don't think that's going to move her up the rankings at all.
Short as she goes in, throwing up the splash, and there's not much of her to throw up splash.
So, yeah, she's off her game this evening, but she'll be back tomorrow in the semi-final.
Well, on our screen, only two have definitely qualified so far, and that is Chen of China and Kristian Sterp.
We have a big queue beside us on the scoreboard, and it tells us who has made it through as they make it through.
At the moment, only two have.
It shows you how tight this competition is.
Kim Won Hyang of Korea, People's Republic of Korea, 19th place.
If this goes right, she will have at least five more dives in this competition.
Oh, I'm sure the whole of the British team were holding their breath because she was in 19th and of course Monique Gladding was in 20th.
Her teammates there really getting behind her and that was a very good dive to finish.
This young lady's been on for a couple of dives and off for a couple and she's finished on a good one there.
That's going to be very close.
I think that will put her above Monique Gladding and so, wow.
Well, Monique's final dive was 67.50 and Kim's final dive was 67.20.
I think there was a big enough margin between the two of them.
That's not going to be closed up sufficiently for Monique at this stage, but there are others still to come.
could fault it along the way.
Brittany Roben has looked pretty impeccable so far.
Here's to finish, back two and a half somersaults, one and a half twists for the young Australian.
Well, she's just a little bit short.
She went in.
She's been really, really impressive.
Not finishing on her best dive though.
Well, certainly she didn't perform that dive at her best.
I was watching this in training and it was certainly better than this.
Finishing a little bit low on the water means that she's short as she goes in.
That's a poor effort by her standards to finish off the competition but she was way up there in the top three almost after fourth round.
Well, it might be her lowest mark of the evening.
It is 57.60 but she has qualified as has Hu of China.
So, both the Chinese through.
Only four have yet got the queue beside their name to indicate that they are through.
So, still
Spaziani with a 2.8 is not going to get there.
Back one and a half somersaults, two and a half twist, 24th place.
That would have to be the best back one and a half she's ever done but even then it probably wouldn't make it.
No, it's a nice dive to finish but no semi-final place for Brenda.
It's from Italy.
She's been okay this evening but a few errors early on meant that she's left herself too much to do.
Low tariff dive to finish two point eight and she won't be featuring in tomorrow morning's semi-final.
So that job at the Royal Albert Hall is probably up for grabs.
She can go and conduct the
Next up is Carolina Hernandez.
of Mexico and she is right on the last qualification position.
No pressure then.
18th place, back two and a half somersaults, one and a half twists.
She and Monique take a long time over their preparation.
Thinking about making a cup of tea now might be a good time.
Oh, there you go.
So, she was an 18th after the fourth round and that is not going to help her campaign.
She will move down the ranks with that.
That does help some of the other women.
Certainly Monique Ladding who is watching now the scoreboard and hoping that she can make it through.
There's nothing Monique can do now but this young lady has just taken herself out of contention.
It's not worked for her.
That's twice now.
She's a laboriously long build up to that dive, and it's not worked for her.
When she went quicker, more quickly, she did much better.
I don't quite... That's the way she does it.
It didn't really work for her tonight.
4.5s, and she moves below Monique Gladding in the standings.
So Monique has made up one place.
Kopchuk has qualified.
As we move on to Rosaline Fillion, 17th for Canada.
No room for error, no margin for mistakes.
Well, no mistakes.
That will keep her in the top eighteen which of course is where she wants to be.
Hasn't had the best day on the diving boards here today.
We can expect to see so much more from this lady.
Of course, she's an Olympic medalist already.
Last week in the Syncro competition with the fellow Canadian who's also featured here today.
Megan Benefito.
So, here we are.
Rosaline in on her head and safely through to the
I think some of the other divers would buy that seven, seven and seven point five off her.
Just to give themselves a bit of insurance, a bit of a buffer, but she's done what she had to do and yeah, gets from the coach and she'll be returning in, well, just over 12 hours from now.
Melissa Wu to finish a back two and a half somersaults, one and a half twists, eighth place.
Melissa on her way.
Yep, Melissa safely on her way, all the way through into the semi-finals.
She's been pretty steady this evening and that's what you needed to do to get through, well, unscathed.
We'll certainly see Melissa in tomorrow morning's semi-final.
Hope you can join us then.
Well, I think the standard will have improved sufficiently and quite markedly from what we're seeing tonight.
Even though it will be early morning dives for the divers, which I don't particularly like.
We might see a few more of them on their game in the semi.
They're the marks for Melissa Wu, the Australian contingent, vocal and numerous.
And 72 is what she gets.
Now Maria Kojo of Germany, 10th place.
She's probably overperformed, if anything, tonight.
Two point nine.
Nice, steady sequence of dives from her.
Back two and a half somersaults.
Yep, very steady and she just plonks that one on her head just as she needs to to make it through safely.
Yeah, very steady.
Solid last round dive.
Two point nine and the backward two and a half in the pike position.
She knows where she is, points the toes back up towards the five, around the five
Very good.
Certainly good enough for a semi-final place.
Underlining her tenth position from the previous round.
Still tenth with that sixty-two point three five.
Already competed in the synchro.
Now in the individual.
She's picking up.
more where she lift off than from the synchro she's gonna act together tonight and uh pang back two and a half for her
Yeah, the back two and a half with one and a half twists.
Lots of the girls finishing on this one.
Almost landing on the camera down there as she went so deep into the water.
Some of you can see this.
Well, some of you are asking about the sprays.
The sprays, of course, disturbed the surface of the water.
So as Pandena comes around here, she can see exactly where the surface of the water is to grab her hands and punch the entry into the water.
She's done a great job out there today.
And she'll certainly be one of the top qualifiers as we go through to the semifinals.
just waiting for her marks to come up before I can confirm her progression.
Yeah, Ben Fito, back key and she goes in as the second highest qualifier so far by Chen.
So so far we have ten people who have confirmed their place.
Here comes Kim
That's very good.
That is good enough to secure a place.
Her teammates are on their feet and so they should be.
She's been working hard out there today.
Very good quality dives and this is one of them.
Could get 70 points on this and if it does, she will
Waiting for the judges to input their marks.
It's about to appear on your screen.
And here they come.
Seven point fives and a seven.
Seventeen point four zero.
Yeah, the big Q is beside her name.
She's the eleventh qualifier for the semifinal.
Not likely to include Anya Rivera of Cuba, but she's got her program to finish off.
And yep, it's that dive again.
And that's a better effort from from Ania.
She's had a tough day out there today.
Some of her dives.
Well, all of her dives actually going amiss.
This one is her best dive of the competition.
Lots of the girls finishing on this one.
Back two and a half somersaults with one and a half twists.
Some taping on the shins there.
Maybe suffering some shin splints.
Quite common in divers because they're constantly doing exercises in order to make their jumps more explosive.
As if they're a hurdler or a sprinter causing great strain.
There we go.
That's her Olympic prelim complete.
57.60.
Monica Gladding waiting.
There's nothing she can do now.
She's had her five dives.
She's reliant on everybody else not getting over that eighteen threshold.
There's a diver ranked twenty-three after round four.
Tracy took it on Malaysia and it's that dive again.
A lot of the divers in the final round opting for the back two and a half.
Here comes
Oh, very good dive there from Tracy.
She, yeah, has struggled a little bit out there, but she's finished very, very strongly there.
Back two and a half somersaults, one and a half twists.
You're getting used to this one now.
3.2 degree of difficulty wraps into the one and a half twists.
And there she is into the water vertically with hardly any splash.
That's a great dive to finish, but just left herself too much to do to make it through to the semifinals.
up to 18th for the time being, but there are plenty more divers to go to knock her still further down, so she will not be returning.
Roslyn Filion has confirmed her return in the semis and 7.5 and 7 as the Malaysian finishes off her campaign.
Okay.
This young lady will win a few hearts just by her preparation alone tonight.
It's been entertaining.
Her diving has been a little bit erratic but she's got it together towards the end.
Thirteenth place.
Obviously, can't see the face on this one.
Now, we can.
Back two and a half somersaults.
One half twist.
It's almost like we're having a conversation here, Katie.
Well,
the past three dives that she's performed have been very good indeed 78 points 78 points and this one i think will be in the 70s once again lots of divers opting just a little bit over vertical as she goes in but that's going to scoot her continuing up the leaderboard she'll certainly be in the top 10
Yeah, we look forward to the continuation of the Katie Bell chat show tomorrow.
She's through with that seventy-two.
I guess she's probably a bit of a chatterbox, don't you?
Now, Espinoza Sanchez, I think for me, that's my biggest disappointment of the night, but she will be back for more provided everything goes to plan on this back two and a half with Pike.
No, it's a back two and a half somersaults with one and a half twists.
Three point two degree of difficulty.
This is an important dive for her to finish on and she needed to finish very well.
Which she does.
We expected to see more from this young lady and I'm sure we will tomorrow.
She's made it through relatively comfortably in the end.
Pretty sure that'll put her in the top twelve.
After a very shaky first two round dive,
Well, let's give you an idea.
Thirty-nine point six in round two but uh back to yeah, the kind of normality to expect from the bronze medalist from last year who I kind of had down for a medal in this competition but she hasn't really backed up my statement with uh performance tonight but that's okay.
Now Monique, kiss to the fans at home who are desperately hoping you're there.
She's seventeenth at the moment.
and it's going to go above her.
Almost certainly fifth after the last round.
Yeah, there's a bit splashy.
She goes in but that will be good enough to take her through to the semifinal.
She went in there.
Her tied out out of the way to get right in your face if you're doing multiple twisting, multiple somersaulting
Marks, please, judges.
Here they come.
Sixty-four for Coltanova.
I think she wanted a bit more than that by look on her face, but it doesn't matter because she can get more tomorrow when she returns for the semifinal.
Now, we don't want to wish her ill, but if this goes well for Nakagawa, there will be no British representation in the semifinal.
So back two and a half again.
landing on the edge of a seat.
Wow, it's good.
Back two and a half somersaults.
One and a half twists in the pike position.
Lots of girls using this one.
Three point two.
And that's Nakagawa through to the semi-final with a solid last round dive.
Let's have a look what that does to the standings and where it moves people to.
Look at that overhead shot.
Just showing you what the girls are attempting to do.
Impressive.
Well, that 70.40 means the home fans will have nobody to support.
They have to adopt somebody in the semifinal because both Monique Gladding and Stacey Powell outside the top 18.
As we welcome for the final time, the last diver of Korea and she'll go for same dive to finish.
Oh, the youngest competitor finishes up the polymeries, only 14 years old.
And I'm sure, well, she must have enjoyed every second.
What an absolute privilege to come and compete at the Olympic Games when you're only 14 years old.
Just over a vertical as she goes in there.
She's going to finish bottom of the pile and she's been there all competition.
I hope she's enjoyed her Olympic experience.
The coach is applauding her efforts and that's her competition complete.
She will finish at the bottom of the standings.
Smile on the face though, she seems to have enjoyed the experience.
And there's Amdila, who will be returning in second place.
Second place qualifier for the Malaysian.
She's still chatting away.
There you are.
She's a right old chatterbox, isn't she?
It's funny, really.
One of the smallest divers in the contest has the tallest coach with her.
It gives you such a contrast, doesn't it?
So here we go.
The standings after round five, the final round in the women's 10 meter platform.
And most of the big names are through.
Pretty much all the big names are through.
China at the top.
China in sixth.
Now, this is the agonizing wait.
For those that already know, I think pretty much all the calculations have been done.
And the last place claimed by Kim of People's Republic of Korea.
Now, who is the unfortunate person just to miss out on the top 18 places?
It is Monique Ladding.
Stacey Powell in twentieth.
So, the two British competitors just missing out in the there'll be the reserves for the semifinal.
And and Brenda Spaziani.
Both thought they'd be in the top eighteen.
It wasn't to be their night tonight or indeed for Anya Rivera.
Consolation for Monique.
Consolation two for Stacey.
And
Big headphones.
We'll be ready to come back for the semi-final, which is 10 o'clock British summer time.
Wherever you're watching around the world, check your clocks and your watches and make sure you're with us.
If it's pretty easy to tell you, it's going to be in 12 and a half hours or so from now, the semi-final of the Women's 10 meter platform.
And I can tell you that Chen was in the end.
43 points above Pang of Malaysia.
Thank you for joining us on our transmission here from the Aquatic Centre at the heart of London's Olympic Park.
Sadly, no British competitors back for the semi-final but eighteen will return as will we.
Look forward to seeing you then.
Bye bye.
Thank you.